《曼达洛人》前情提要
就是它
This is the one.
它看上去挺没用的
It looks helpless.
它并非无用
It is not helpless.
它的种族可以通过意念移动物体
Its species can move objects with its mind.
万古之前的诗歌中
The songs of eons past
记载了曼达洛大帝
tell of battles between Mandalore The Great,
和一个叫绝地武士的巫师教团之间的战争
and an order of sorcerers called Jedi
他们就会运用这种力量进行战斗
that fought with such powers.
-那它是什么  -它是弃婴
- What is it? - It is a foundling.
根据信条  你得负责照顾它
By Creed, it is in your care.
你希望我在整个星系中找到它的家
You expect me to search the galaxy
还要把他送回
for the home of this creature and
敌对的巫师族
deliver it to a race of enemy sorcerers?
此乃正道
This is the Way.
我被要求
I've been quested
把这个孩子交给绝地武士
with returning this Child to the Jedi.
我可以带你找到他们的同类
I can lead you to one of their kind.
但首先  我们的任务需要你的帮助
But first, we need your help on our mission.
我们得拖住他们
We need to hold them off
直到我们可以进入超空间
until we can make the jump to hyperspace.
我在哪能找到绝地武士
Where can I find the Jedi?
带弃婴去卡洛丹
Take the foundling to the city of Calodan
在乌鸦座的森林星球上
on the forest planet of Corvus.
阿索卡·塔诺就在那里
There you will find Ahsoka Tano.
告诉她是博·卡坦让你去找她的
Tell her you were sent by Bo-Katan.
谢谢你
And thank you.
你的英勇我会铭记在心
Your bravery will not be forgotten.
此乃正道
This is the Way.
星球大战
瞄准镜看不到她  把她赶出来
She's off the scope. Draw her out.
我看不到了  扫描移动物体
I've lost visual. Scan for movement.
现身吧
Show yourself.
绝地武士
Jedi.
我一直在等你来呢
I've been expecting you.
那你知道我想要什么了
Then you know what I want.
我什么也不会告诉你
You will learn nothing from me.
我让你没得选
I won't give you that choice.
我所拥有的信息对你来说值几条命
How many lives is the knowledge I possess worth to you?
一条
One?
十条
Ten?
一百条怎么样
How about a hundred?
这些平民的命对我来说毫无意义
The lives of these citizens mean nothing to me.
而因为你  这些人要受苦了
Now, because of you, these people will suffer.
他们在你的治下已经受尽苦难
They already suffer under your rule.
投降吧  否则后果自负
Surrender, or face the consequences.
给你一天时间做出决定
You have one day to decide.
她回来时我们会做好准备的
We will be ready when she returns.
把他装笼子里
Cage him.
曼达洛人
第二季第五集
第十三章
绝地武士
乌鸦座  就是这了
Corvus, this is the place.
我探测到了一个信标
I've detected a beacon.
我要开始着陆程序
I'm gonna start the landing cycle.
你最好回你的座位去
You better get back in your seat.
我怎么跟你说的
Hey, what did I tell you?
回你座位去
Back in your seat.
那个我是怎么跟你说的
What did I say about that?
这个要留在船上
This needs to stay in the ship.
这里没什么可看的
Not much to see out here.
从没和绝地武士打过交道
Never had dealings with a Jedi before.
我们去城里吧
Let's head into town.
看看我们能否找到个线索
See if we can pick up a lead.
来者何事
State your business.
追踪了几天了
Been tracking for a few days.
想找个地方落落脚
Looking for a layover.
盔甲不错啊
Nice armor.
那你是个猎人了
You a hunter, then?
是的
That's right.
公会的
Guild?
如假包换
Last I checked.
打开城门
Open the gate.
打扰一下  商家  你听说过...
Pardon me, vendor, have you heard of anyone...
这位
You there.
我需要了解点事
I need some information.
我在找人
I'm looking for someone.
好了  再见
Okay, bye.
求求你  不要和他们或者我们中的任何人说话
Please, do not speak to them, or to any of us.
听着  我只是想打听...
Look, I just need to know...
地方官想见你
The Magistrate wants to see you.
救救我们
Help us.
她会把我们都杀了
She'll kill us all.
上前来
Come forward.
你是个曼达洛人
You are a Mandalorian?
是的
Yes.
我有个提议你可能会感兴趣
I have a proposition that may interest you.
我要价很高的
My price is high.
这个目标是无价的
This target is priceless.
一个绝地武士困扰着我
A Jedi plagues me.
我想让你杀了她
I want you to kill her.
这任务很困难
That's a difficult task.
很合适你的任务
One that you are well-suited for.
绝地武士是曼达洛星球的古老敌人
The Jedi are the ancient enemy of Mandalore.
如我所说  我的要价很高的
As I said, my price is high.
你觉得这个怎么样
What do you make of this?
曼达洛铁
Beskar.
纯曼达洛铁
Pure beskar.
就像你的盔甲一样
Like your armor.
杀了绝地武士  它就归你了
Kill the Jedi and it's yours.
在哪里可以找到这个绝地武士
Where do I find this Jedi?
那是什么
What is that thing?
我随身带着以求好运
I keep it around for luck.
等你到了那里  会需要好运的
You're gonna need it where you're headed.
这些是坐标
Well, these are the coordinates.
睁大眼睛
Keep your eyes open.
我们离目标不远了
We must be close.
听见了吗
You hear that?
别担心  在这坐一下  我看看情况
Don't worry. Sit right here. Let me see what's out there.
虚惊一场
False alarm.
阿索卡·塔诺
Ahsoka Tano!
博·卡坦让我来的
Bo-Katan sent me.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
希望是关于他的事
I hope it's about him.
他在说话吗
Is he speaking?
你能明白他的话吗
Do you understand him?
某种程度上可以
In a way.
格罗古和我可以感知对方的思想
Grogu and I can feel each other's thoughts.
格罗古
Grogu?
没错
Yes.
这是他的名字
That's his name.
格罗古
Grogu.
他在科洛桑的绝地圣殿长大
He was raised at the Jedi Temple on Coruscant.
多年来  有许多大师训练了他
Many Masters trained him over the years.
克隆战争结束时  帝国崛起
At the end of the Clone Wars when the Empire rose to power,
他被藏了起来
he was hidden.
有人把他带出了圣殿
Someone took him from the Temple.
接着他的记忆就变得模糊了
Then his memory becomes... dark.
他似乎很迷茫
He seemed lost.
很孤独
Alone.
我只认识一位他的同类
I've only known one other being like this.
一位名叫尤达的绝地大师
A wise Jedi Master named Yoda.
他还能运用原力吗
Can he still wield the Force?
你是指他的力量吗
You mean his powers?
是原力给了他力量
The Force is what gives him his powers.
它是所有生物创造出的能量场
It is an energy field created by all living things.
运用原力需要大量的训练和修养
To wield it takes a great deal of training and discipline.
我见过他做出让我无法解释的事
I've seen him do things I can't explain.
我的任务是把他带给一个绝地武士
My task was to bring him to a Jedi.
绝地武士团很久之前就陷落了
The Jedi Order fell a long time ago.
帝国也一样  可帝国依然对他穷追不舍
So did the Empire, yet it still hunts him.
他需要你的帮助
He needs your help.
让他睡吧
Let him sleep.
明早我会对他进行测试
I'll test him in the morning.
看看他的小脑袋里藏了什么知识
Let's see what knowledge is lurking inside that little mind.
格罗古  把石头还给我
Now, return the stone to me, Grogu.
他不明白你的意思
He doesn't understand.
他明白
He does.
没事的
It's okay.
石头  格罗古
The stone, Grogu.
我能感觉到你很害怕
I sense much fear in you.
多年来  他依靠隐藏自己的能力偷生
He's hidden his abilities to survive over the years.
试试别的吧
Let's try something else.
过来
Come over here.
-他很固执  -我没叫他
- He's stubborn. - Not him.
我叫你
You.
我想看看他会不会听你的话
I want to see if he'll listen to you.
这还是第一次
That would be a first.
我喜欢第一次
I like firsts.
无论好坏都值得纪念
Good or bad, they're always memorable.
把石头放在掌心上
Now, hold the stone out in the palm of your hand.
让他举起石头
Tell him to lift it up.
好了  孩子
All right, kid.
把石头举起来
Lift the stone.
格罗古
Grogu.
Grogu...
来  拿走石头
Come on, take the stone.
你看
You see?
我说了  他很固执
I told you, he's stubborn.
试试和他心灵相通
Try to connect with him.
格罗古
Grogu...
你想要这个吗
Do you want this?
拿走吧
Well, go ahead.
没错  拿走它
That's right, take it.
来  给你了
Come on. You can have it.
来
Come on.
好样的
Good job!
好样的  孩子
Good job, kid.
看到了吗
You see that?
这就对了
That's right.
我就知道你能行
I knew you could do it.
很棒
Very good.
他对你产生了很强的依赖
He's formed a strong attachment to you.
我无法训练他
I cannot train him.
什么
What?
为什么
Why not?
你看到了他的能力
You've seen what he can do.
他对你的依赖会让他容易被恐惧控制
His attachment to you makes him vulnerable to his fears.
还有他的愤怒
His anger.
那就更应该训练他了
All the more reason to train him.
不
No.
我见过这样的感觉
I've seen what such feelings can do
能对训练有素的绝地武士产生什么影响
to a fully trained Jedi Knight.
最优秀的绝地武士
To the best of us.
我不会让这个孩子走那条路的
I will not start this child down that path.
还是让他的能力消失吧
Better to let his abilities fade.
我耽搁太久了  我回村庄了
I've delayed too long. I must get back to the village.
地方官派我来杀你
The Magistrate sent me to kill you.
我什么都没同意
I didn't agree to anything.
我可以帮你解决问题
And I'll help you with your problem,
只要你保证格罗古可以得到良好的训练
if you see to it that Grogu is properly trained.
她有装备A350爆能枪  两个HK-87
She has a small army of guards armed with A350 blaster rifles,
杀手机器人  和一个雇佣枪手的警卫部队
two HK-87 assassin droids, and a hired gunfighter.
我感觉他是退伍军人
He reads ex-military to me.
如果他们集中火力  就算是你的光剑
Combined, not even your laser swords
都抵挡不了他们的攻击
would be able to protect you from all that firepower.
是的
True.
但也不要小看地方官
But don't underestimate the Magistrate either.
她是谁
Who is she?
她愿意用纯曼达洛铁杖雇我杀你
She offered me a staff of pure beskar to kill you.
摩根·埃尔斯贝思
Morgan Elsbeth.
克隆人战争期间  她的人民惨遭屠杀
During the Clone Wars, her people were massacred.
她活了下来  她的怒火让她东山再起
She survived and let her anger fuel an industry
并帮助建造了帝国星际舰队
which helped build the Imperial Starfleet.
她掠夺了世界  并在这个过程中摧毁了一切
She plundered worlds, destroying them in the process.
是啊  看来她还没有罢休
Yeah, it looks like she's still in business.
你在城里的时候见过囚犯吗
When you were in the city did you see any prisoners?
我看见三个村民被吊在内门外
I saw three villagers strung up just outside the inner gate.
我们必须解救他们
We must find a way to free them.
曼达洛人和绝地武士联手
A Mandalorian and a Jedi?
他们肯定想不到的
They'll never see it coming.
是她  敲响警报
It's her! Sound the alarm!
你的赏金猎人失败了
Your bounty hunter failed.
把我想知道的告诉我
Tell me what I want to know.
你的主人呢
Where is your master?
杀了她
Kill her.
乐意效劳
Love to.
我来解决她
I'll take care of this.
带上他们
Take them with you.
处决他们
Execute them.
然后挨家挨户  全杀了
Then go door to door.
求你了  不要
Please, don't!
上去
Get up there!
-进去  -走
- Get inside! - go.
你和绝地武士联手了
So, you threw in with the Jedi.
看起来是的
Looks that way.
你觉得谁会赢
Who do you think's gonna win?
可能是你的人
Could be your side...
可能是我的人
could be my side.
我和你没有过节  曼达洛人
I got no quarrel with you, Mandalorian.
够近了
That's far enough.
咱俩很像
You and I, we're a lot alike.
愿意为大业献出生命
Willing to lay our lives down for the right cause.
但这次不是
Which this is not.
听上去你赢了
Sounds like you win.
后面
Behind you!
告诉我
Now, tell me.
你的主人在哪里
Where is your master?
索龙元帅在哪里
Where is Grand Admiral Thrawn?
这是你原来的报酬吧
I believe this was your payment.
不
No.
我不能接受
I can't accept.
我没有完成任务
I didn't finish the job.
的确
No.
但这属于曼达洛人
But this belongs with a Mandalorian.
你的小朋友呢
Where is your little friend?
在飞船上
Back at the ship.
在这儿等着  我去叫他
Wait here, I'll go get him.
醒醒  伙计
Wake up, buddy.
是时候道别了
It's time to say goodbye.
你就像他父亲一样
You're like a father to him.
我不能训练他
I cannot train him.
咱们说好的  我已经履行了承诺
You made me a promise, and I held up my end.
有一种可能
There is one possibility.
去泰桑星球
Go to the planet Tython.
那里有一座与原力
You will find the ancient ruins of a temple
有着紧密联系的古代圣殿遗迹
that has a strong connection to the Force.
把格罗古放在山顶的观景石上
Place Grogu on the seeing stone at the top of the mountain.
然后呢
Then what?
然后让格罗古选择他的道路
Then Grogu may choose his path.
如果他释放出原力
If he reaches out through the Force,
绝地武士可能会感知到他的存在
there's a chance a Jedi may sense his presence
然后来找他
and come searching for him.
但是话说回来
Then again,
绝地武士不多了
there aren't many Jedi left.
谢谢
Thank you.
愿原力与你同在
May the Force be with you.